Contact

hrushig@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/hrushig (LinkedIn) www.wipo.int/pctdb/en/wo.jsp (Other)

Top Skills

Systems Engineering Email Archiving Performance Testing

Languages

English

Kannada

Hindi

Certifications

Certified Software Test Engineer (CSTE)

Microsoft Certified System Engineer (MCSE): 2000 Track

VERITAS Certified Professional (VCP): Backup Exec 9 Windows Servers

Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA)

Certified Support Professional (CSP)

Publications

Headless NFVi for PoP, CO or MSC MSO

Patents

Federated Virtual Datacenter Apparatus

Enterprise server version migration through identity preservation

Hrushikesh Gangur

Sr. Solutions Architect, AWS

San Francisco, California

Summary

I have in total 20+ years of experience in IT that includes 4+ years in Cloud technologies like OpenStack, SDN Controllers, vSwitches, Virtual Storage, KVM/ESX hypervisors and 9+ years of specialization in archiving/data protection applications and their underlying sub-systems. Interest work areas are – design and architect cloud products/solutions for telcos and enterprises, software defined networking, scalability and performance analytics, sizing/deployment/best practices guidelines, extensive customer interactions for requirements gathering and function specs, deployment, managing and administering enterprise/telco grade labs, provide implementation details to dev/test/field engineers.

Cloud Technologies: OpenStack, SDN Controllers, vSwitches Specialties: Storage: 3Par, LHN Store Virtual, NetApp, LSI, Cirtas, DELL, Data Domain, Promise, Ceph, nfs-ha

OS: Ubuntu, Debian, Wind River, Windows Server 2008/2003 R2 Virtualization: KVM, Windows Server 2008 Hyper-V, VMWare ESX

Messaging: MS Exchange Server, Send Mail (Linux) Big Data technologies: Kafka, Storm, ElasticSearch

Database: MS SQL Server, MySQL, Postgres SQL, MongoDB Archiving/Backup: IRM NearPoint for Exchange/FileSystem/ SharePoint, IBM Tivoli Storage Manager, Symantec Backup Exec,

Oracle URM, Actiance Alcatraz

Tools: Windows Performance Counter, collectl, Ganglia, other linux perf tools - iostat, top, mongotop

Experience

Amazon Web Services (AWS) Sr. Solutions Architect February 2019 - Present

San Francisco, California

Actiance, Inc.

Technical Director, Performance and Instrumentation March 2017 - January 2019 (1 year 11 months)

Redwood City, California

Lead and drive performance engineering of compliance and archiving products. Includes:

- Define, regulate and evaluate Key Performance Metrics of the product and gate releases
- Lead a group of test and performance engineers, provide guidance, review test plan, test cases, analysis and reports
- Run specialized perf tests for R&A library comparison, mongo sharding, nfs-ha (drbd), Ceph tuning, multi-datapath
- Provide deployment (multi-node, billions of records) sizing guidelines based on product's resource footprint, best practices and tuning parameter
- Performance troubleshooting, analyze customer's data and environment (heapdump), and provide solution

Lead and enrich a group of engineers to be Subject Matter Expert in key technologies - Kafka, Ceph, Mongo, ElasticSearch, this includes:

- Own one or two technologies ceph, kafka, nfs-ha best practices, deployment guidelines, tuning, troubleshooting and administration. Create documentation and handing it over to Ops.
- Build roadmap and execute on upcoming upgrades, features, resiliency testing and incremental scaling of these technologies

Hewlett Packard Enterprise

4 years 9 months

Distinguished Technologist and Architect, Helion OpenStack Carrier Grade and NFV System

December 2014 - March 2017 (2 years 4 months)

Sunnyvale, CA

Understanding customer requirements (MRDs, PRDs), breaking down into technical requirements - functional specs, choosing right technologies or technology partners, coming up with block, network, component architecture. Demonstrating and presenting architectural and sequence diagrams to Dev/Test engineers, internal and/or 3rd party partners. Focussed areas: OpenStack, SDN Controllers (DCN), Wind River Linux KVM, VMWare ESX

Customer facing interaction includes - customer visits, providing demos, detailed solution architecture and implementation know how, gather additional

requirements that a product doesn't meet and come with design/specs for integration tools. In few cases, end to end deployment of the solution at a customer site, involve in escalations on critical production issues, visiting customer to provide RCA deep dive.

Master Technologist, Performance and Solutions July 2012 - December 2014 (2 years 6 months) Sunnyvale, CA

Performance characterization of various cloud products based on OpenStack. This involves planning, designing, setting up the platform to cover perf and scale test cases. Coming up with best practices recommendation.

Solution Engineering involves providing a custom solution and design/ develop modules where there are product gaps. Implementation at customer environment, running through pre-production and hand-off to technical support. Engaging with field engineers or professional services in help guide deployment of uniquely positioned customers.

Autonomy, an HP Company Manager, Software Engineering June 2011 - July 2012 (1 year 2 months) San Jose, CA

Same as mentioned in Iron Mountain Job Description

Iron Mountain
Manager, Software Engineering
April 2010 - June 2011 (1 year 3 months)
Mountain View. CA

Utilize deep and specialized knowledge of IRM NearPoint™ for Microsoft® Exchange Server for Enterprise Customers worldwide. Architect new features and designs for core IRM NearPoint™ for Microsoft® Exchange Server in relation to Hosting (Archiving in cloud), large and complex Customer deployments:

Evaluating, Reviewing and Providing relevant data and feedback to Architects in getting NearPoint enablement for Cloud Archiving

Deliver and Roll out IRM NearPoint™ for Microsoft® Exchange Server to Enterprise Accounts. Pre-flight, Corner Case Test, Support and Hand off to Support upon successful Customer Sign off. Direct Customer interactions with Worldwide Customer base

Deliver Turn Key Customer Solutions which roll up as design spec into GA Build:

Managing a team of Principal Performance Engineer and Lead QA engineers to deliver Email, PST, File Archiving Sizing, Scalability and Performance Best Practices to Customers and internal Support.

Design and develop tests for the storage management, back-up/restore management, replication, disaster recovery and high availability features of IRM NearPoint™ for Microsoft® Exchange Server;

Design and develop automated tests for end to end functionality, robustness, performance, and scalability testing for IRM NearPoint™ for Microsoft® Exchange Server; and

Design and develop compatibility testing of IRM NearPoint[™] for Microsoft® Exchange Server with a variety of server and client platforms, storage platforms, and server and client environments and configurations

Mimosa Systems 2 years 7 months

Manager, Solutions Engineering October 2009 - April 2010 (7 months)

Same as mentioned in Iron Mountain Job Description

Sr. Systems Engineer, Solutions Engineering Group October 2007 - September 2009 (2 years)

Driving enterprise, scalability, sizing and performance requirements targeted for the product release.

Develop and execute tests for black box, white box, gray box testing of Mimosa products.

Develop and execute tests for the storage management, back-up/restore management, replication, disaster recovery and high availability features of Mimosa products.

Develop tests for end to end functionality, robustness, performance, and scalability testing for our products.

Develop and execute compatibility testing of our products with a variety of server and client platforms, storage platforms and server and client environments and configurations.

Developing systems and solutions best practices guidelines for Mimosa products

Handling projects for sales/pre-sales/support with sizing and interesting onsite POC Demos

Symphony Services Pvt. Ltd.
Lead QA Engineer
March 2005 - September 2007 (2 years 7 months)
Pune, India

Working in a close-knit with Developers in designing, development and testing of modules

QA of modules based on functionality, usability, performance and error handling

Test Plan and its execution based on White Box and Black Box testing

Carrying out adhoc tests and smoke tests

Customer's scenario simulation and providing valuable feedback to developers

Setting up complex environments: Multiple forest and complex domain environments. Clustering of Exchange Servers, Multiple exchange servers and administrative groups

VERITAS Software

Team Lead

February 2002 - March 2005 (3 years 2 months)

Managing, Coaching/Mentoring and Leading 10 technically qualified engineers

Handling escalations, complex and critical calls

Providing various Storage Solutions to engineers as well customers

Explaining finer details of the product such as Architecture to trained engineers through presentations/practicals

Help engineers develop their troubleshooting and analytical skills

Keeping engineers abreast of latest technological trends like SAN, NAS and Multi-Stage Backup technologies

Attending/Conducting teleconference with US/EMEA/AUS counterparts in both technical and process area

Maintaining SLA by keeping track of customer queries and escalations and preparing a detailed report of the same

Conducting interviews for replacement hiring

Carrying out performance evaluations every six months for the team members

Delegating work to team members in the team and oversee the progress of the projects.

Setting up the development plans for the team members

Evaluating customer satisfaction surveys and striving to optimize the support model

Helping QA for beta testing of the new products

MAHYCO Life Science Research Center, Jalna, India IT Consultant
February 2001 - September 2001 (8 months)
Jalna, India

Planning, installing, configuring & administration of LINUX, SCO UNIX & Novell NetWare Server. Installing & Configuring VPN & Internet Security (IP Chains).

Participate and consult in the planning above said Infrastructure, design and integration of new LAN & WAN technologies into the network management system.

To monitor & troubleshoot MW Link, leased line circuit connectivity and VSAT links and to co-ordinate with COMSATMAX & DOT for maximum up-time.

To install, configure & maintain Cisco 2500/Motorola 6450/6425 Routers & switches

To install, configure & maintain total health of Mail Server (Sendmail, MHS), Web Server (Apache), File Server (Netware 4.11) & Proxy server (Squid).

To configure, administer & Maintain DHCP & DNS (Bind 9.1) servers over various zones

To take & maintain proper data backup's. (Incremental/Full)

To reply & co-ordinate with branch office IT problems either through e-mail or telephone.

To install & configure common applications. To provide extreme user level comfort for users working on Windows 95/98, Pegasus Mail, Network printing & file management.

Centre for Electronics Design & Technology of India, Aurangabad Network Administrator

August 1995 - February 2001 (5 years 7 months)

Aurangabad, India

Designing, Implementation & overall administration of CEDTIA Network Infrastructure

Planning, installing, configuring & administration of Windows NT 4.0, Migration to Windows 2000 Advanced Server & Novell NetWare 5.0/4.11, Exchange Server 5.5.

Directs, manages, plans and administers the operational and administrative activities of Network Management area considering organizations security policies.

Inventory Management: Procurement of H/W & S/W.

To install, configure & administer IIS 5.0 & Web hosting (www.cedti.com)

Cisco Router Management: Installing & configuration of Cisco 2500 router.

To monitor & troubleshoot leased line connectivity and to co-ordinate with DOT for up-time.

To install, configure & administer Oracle 8i, SQL Server 7.0, Exchange Server 5.5, MS Proxy Server, Application (AMD, CADSTAR, MSOFFICE) & File Server.

User administration with creating and maintain user account with changes in user allocation of resources like disk usage, file & print access, software installation etc.

To take & maintain proper data backup's

To provide extreme user level comfort for users working on Windows NT/98, MS Exchange 5.5, Network printing & file management.

Maintenance of Different types of IBM compatible PCs & Peripherals

Solving day-to-day user software and hardware problems.

Education

Government Engineering College, Aurangabad
BE (Equivalent to BS), Electronics and Telecommunication · (1996 - 2001)

Centre for Electronics Design and Technology of India, Aurangabad Diploma, Electronics Production and Maintenance (1992 - 1995)

Kendriya Vidyalaya

K-12, Maths and Science · (1981 - 1991)